Guide to the Ann Cornelisen Papers, 1714-1994 (bulk 1954-1990)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series IV Photographs
  - Contact Sheets and Contact Prints
    - Contact Sheets
      - "nos. 121-130" (14.14)
      - "nos. 131-140" (14.15)
      - "nos. 141-150" (14.16)
      - "nos. 151-160" (14.17)
      - "nos. 161-170" (14.18)
      - "nos. 171-175" (14.19)
      - Portrait of unidentified woman (22.5)
    - Contact Prints
      - "no. 84" (50.8)
      - "no. 134" (50.9)
      - "no. 141" (50.10)
      - [no. 182] (50.11)
      - [no. 186] (50.12)
      - [no. 190] (50.48)
      - [no. 191] (50.49)
      - [no. 193] (50.50)
      - [no. 194] (50.51)
      - [no. 195] (50.52)
      - [no. 197] (50.53)
      - [no. 198] (50.54)
      - [no. 212] (50.13)
      - [no. 215] (50.14)
      - [no. 217] (50.15)
      - [no. 218] (50.16)
      - [no. 219] (50.17)
      - [no. 237] (50.18)
      - [no. 244] (50.19)
      - [no. 245] (50.20)
      - [no. 248] (50.21)
      - [no. 256] (50.22)
      - [no. 258] (50.23)
      - [no. 259] (50.24)
      - [no. 262] (50.25)
      - [no. 271] (50.26)
      - [no. 276] (50.27)
      - [no. 277] (50.28)
      - [no. 278] (50.29)
      - [no. 279] (50.30)
      - [no. 280] (50.31)
      - [no. 281] (50.32)
      - [no. 282] (50.33)
      - [no. 283] (50.34)
      - [no. 285] (50.35)
      - [no. 293] (50.36)
      - [no. 296] (50.37)
      - [no. 309] (50.38)
      - [no. 310] (50.39)
      - [no. 311] — Ralph Cornelisen and Ann Cornelisen — informal portraits (50.40)
      - [no. 312] (50.41)
      - [no. 316] (50.42)
      - [no. 317] (50.43)
      - [no. 324] (50.44)
      - [no. 330] (50.45)
      - [no. 334] (50.46)
      - [no. 343] (50.47)
  - Slides
    - Original Container 1, 1964, n.d. (F. 15.1 - 15.2)
    - Original Container 2 - "Tric. # 1,", 1967, n.d. (F. 15.3 - 15.4)
    - Original Container 3, 1967, n.d. (F. 15.5 - 15.6)
    - Original Container 4, 1967, n.d. (F. 15.7 - 15.8)
    - Original Container 5, 1967, n.d. (F. 15.9 - 15.10)
    - Original Container 6, 1967, n.d. (F. 15.11 - 15.13)
    - Original Container 7, n.d. (F. 15.14 - 15.16)
    - Original Container 8, n.d. (F. 15.17 - 15.19)
    - Original Container 9, n.d. (F. 15.20 - 15.21)
    - Original Container 10, May 1967 (F. 15.22 - 15.23)
    - Original Container 11, 1967-1968, n.d. (F. 15.24 - 15.25)
    - Original Container 12, July 1968 (F. 15.26 - 15.27)
    - Original Container 13, July 1968 (F. 15.28 - 15.29)
    - Original Container 14, May 1969 (F. 15.30 - 15.31)
    - Original Container 15, May 1969 (F. 15.32 - 15.33)
    - Original Container 16, 1967, n.d. (F. 15.34 - 16.1)
    - Original Container 17, 1967, 1971, n.d. (F. 16.2 - 16.3)
    - Original Container 18, 1967, n.d. (F. 16.4 - 16.5)
    - Original Container 19, 1967-1969, n.d. (F. 16.6 - 16.7)
    - Original Container 20, 1967,1969, n.d. (F. 16.8 - 16.9)
    - Original Container 21, 1967, 1971, n.d. (F. 16.10 - 16.11)
    - Original Container 22, 1968, n.d. (F. 16.12 - 16.13)
    - Original Container 23, 1968, 1971, 1972, n.d. (F. 16.14 - 16.15)
    - Original Container 24, 1967, n.d. (F. 16.16 - 16.17)
    - Original Container 25 - "Rome,", 1967, 1969, n.d. (F. 16.18 - 16.19)
    - Original Container 26, 1967, 1969, 1972, n.d. (F. 16.20 - 16.21)
    - Original Container 27, 1969, 1972, n.d. (F. 16.22 - 16.23)
    - Original Container 28, 1964, n.d. (F. 16.24 - 16.25)
    - Original Container 29, 1967-1968, n.d. (F. 16.26 - 16.27)
    - Original Container 30, Sept. 1967 (F. 16.28 - 16.29)
    - Original Container 31, Sept. 1969 (F. 16.30 - 16.31)
    - Original Container 32, Jan. 1970 (F. 16.32 - 16.33)
    - Original Container 33 - "Calciano, Mar. 72," (F. 16.34 - 17.1)
    - Original Container 34 - "Turi-Callz, Mar. 1972" (F. 17.2 - 17.3)
    - Original Container 35, Oct. 1972 (F. 17.4 - 17.5)
    - Original Container 36, June 1973 (F. 17.6 - 17.7)
    - Original Container 37, June 1973 (F. 17.8 - 17.9)
    - Original Container 38 - "Cortona,", 1974, n.d. (F. 17.10 - 17.11)
    - Original Container 39, 1968, n.d. (F. 17.12 - 17.13)
    - Original Container 40, n.d. (F. 17.14 - 17.16)
    - Original Container 41, n.d. (F. 17.17 - 17-19)
    - Original Container 42, n.d. (F. 17.20 - 17.22)
    - Original Container 43, n.d. (F. 17.23 - 17.24)
    - Metal Case (list included in box) (F. 17.25 - 17.34)
    - Loose, 1967-1972, n.d. (F. 17.35 - 17.38)
    - Loose 7 x 7 inch slides (F. 17.39 - 17.45)
- Series V. Postcards
  - Austria, 1954-1977 (19.24)
  - France, 1955, 1960, n.d. (19.25)
  - Great Britain, 1957, 1960 (19.26)
  - Great Britain, 1967-1970 (19.27)
  - Great Britain - Blank (19.28)
  - Great Britain - Blank (19.29)
  - Great Britain - Blank (19.30)
  - Great Britain - Blank (19.31)
  - Greece, 1964 (19.32)
  - Greece, 1965 (19.33)
  - Greece, 1972 (19.34)
  - Italy – Altamura, 1955, n.d. (18.4)
  - Italy – Arezzo, 1969-1976 (18.5)
  - Italy - Ascoli Piceno, n.d. (18.6)
  - Italy – Bari, 1956-1971 (18.7)
  - Italy – Barletta, 1955-1962 (18.8)
  - Italy – Bergamo, n.d. (18.9)
  - Italy – Bitonto, 1961, 1962, n.d. (18.10)
  - Italy – Bologna, 1956, 1963 (18.11)
  - Italy - Cantoniera della Presolana, 1956 (18.12)
  - Italy - Castel di Sangro, 1956-1967 (18.13)
  - Italy – Catanzaro, 1960, n.d. (18.14)
  - Italy – Colobraro, 1956 (18.15)
  - Italy – Como, 1955 (18.16)
  - Italy – Cortona, 1973-1986 (18.17)
  - Italy – Crotone, 1956, 1960, 1961 (18.18)
  - Italy – Elba, 1968 (18.19)
  - Italy – Firenze, 1954, 1963, n.d. (18.20)
  - Italy – Foggia, 1955-1967 (18.21)
  - Italy – Fossacesia, 1954, n.d. (18.22)
  - Italy – Genova, 1955 (18.23)
  - Italy - L'Aquila, 1967, n.d. (18.24)
  - Italy – Lecce, 1963 (18.3)
  - Italy – Maratea, 1960 (18.3)
  - Italy – Matera, 1955-1962 (18.25)
  - Italy – Matera, n.d. (18.26)
  - Italy – Milano, 1955-1960, n.d. (18.27)
  - Italy – Milano, 1960, n.d. (18.1)
  - Italy – Montecassino, 1957, 1961 (18.28)
  - Italy – Napoli, 1961, n.d. (18.29)
  - Italy – Orgosolo, 1961 (18.3)
  - Italy – Ortona, 1955-1960 (18.30)
  - Italy - Ortona, n.d. (18.31)
  - Italy – Ravello, 1962-1977 (18.32)
  - Italy – Ravenna, 1954, 1963 (18.33)
  - Italy - Roma - Campidoglio (18.34)
  - Italy - Roma - Colisee (18.35)
  - Italy - Roma - Fontana di Trevi (18.2)
  - Italy - Roma - Foro Romano (18.36)
  - Italy - Roma - Pantheon (18.37)
  - Italy - Roma - Trinita dei Monti (18.38)
  - Italy - Roma - Modern Buildings (18.39)
  - Italy - Roma - Streets (18.40)
  - Italy - Roma - Art and Artists' Renditions (18.41)
  - Italy - Roma - Art and Artists' Renditions (18.42)
  - Italy - Roma - Miscellaneous (18.43)
  - Italy - Roma - Miscellaneous (18.44)
  - Italy – Scanno, 1967, n.d. (18.45)
  - Italy – Siena, 1954-1978, n.d. (18.46)
  - Italy – Spoleto, 1973, 1975, n.d. (18.47)
  - Italy – Sulmona, 1955, n.d. (18.48)
  - Italy – Taormina, circa 1955 (18.49)
  - Italy – Tivoli, 1955 (18.50)
  - Italy – Torino, 1955 (18.51)
  - Italy - Tricarico - Piazza Garibaldi (19.1)
  - Italy - Tricarico - Convento di S. Antonio (19.2)
  - Italy - Tricarico - Torre di S. Chiara (19.3)
  - Italy - Tricarico - Panorama del Rione Nuovo (19.4)
  - Italy - Tricarico - Panorama, black and white (19.5)
  - Italy - Tricarico - Panorama, color (19.6)
  - Italy - Tricarico - Panorama, color (19.7)
  - Italy - Tricarico - Mortier woodcut (19.8)
  - Italy - Tricarico - Miscellaneous (19.9)
  - Italy – Venezia, 1960-1963 (19.10)
  - Italy – Venezia, 1971, n.d. (19.11)
  - Italy – Verona, 1963, 1969, n.d. (19.12)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous, A-B (19.13)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous, C-D (19.14)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous, G-L (19.15)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous, M (19.16)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous, N-O (19.17)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous, P (19.18)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous, R (19.19)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous, S (19.20)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous, T-V (19.21)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous (19.22)
  - Italy - Miscellaneous (19.23)
  - Spain, 1965 (19.35)
  - Miscellaneous - Other Countries (19.36)
  - Miscellaneous - Boats and Planes (19.37)
- Series IV. Maps and Posters
  - Poster - Cortona - town view, 1980 (map case 35)
  - Poster - Cortona - seal (29.1)
  - Poster - Cortona - piazza (29.1)
  - Poster - Deem art collection showing her photo, 1975 (map case 35)
  - Map - Modern Italy with Abruzzi and Lucania highlighted (29.4)
  - Map - Tricarico, Italy (29.7)
  - Map - Basilicata, Italy (29.8)
  - Map - Calabria, Italy, 1714 (29.9)
  - Map – Naples, 1750 (map case 35)
- Series VII. Audio Tapes
  - Copies of original enclosures (23.1)
  - Chichella, no. 1, circa 1963-1964 (23.2)
  - Chichella, no. 2, circa 1963-1964 (23.3)
  - Chichella, no. 3, circa 1963-1964 (23.4)
  - Chichella, no. 4, circa 1963-1964 (23.5)
  - Chichella, no. 6, circa 1963-1964 (23.6)
  - Chichella, no. 7, circa 1963-1964 (23.7)
  - Chichella, no. 8, circa 1963-1964 (23.8)
  - Chichella, no. 9, circa 1963-1964 (23.9)
  - Chichella, no. 11, circa 1963-1964 (23.10)
  - Chichella, no. 12, circa 1963-1964 (23.11)
  - "Ferrarotti, no. 1" (23.12)
  - "Ferrarotti, no. 2" (23.13)
  - "Jimmy Crosse" (23.14)
  - "Folk Songs - Tuscany" (23.15)
  - Unidentified, possibly blank (23.16 -23.22)
  - "Mrs. Porter, N.C.B., erased,", Feb. 1969 (23.23)
  - "Mrs. Porter, N.C.B., erased,", Feb. 1969 (23.24)